<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Artistic Portfolio of Chris Ried</title>
    <link>https://chrisried.xyz/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Artistic Portfolio of Chris Ried</description>
    <image>
      <url>https://chrisried.xyz/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://chrisried.xyz/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://chrisried.xyz/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://chrisried.xyz/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2022 21:38:52 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chrisried.xyz/about/</guid>
      <description>Hi! My name is Chris Ried! I am a artist who loves to learn and who happens to use technology to mine it. I&amp;rsquo;ve spent much of the last 10 years exploring many different mediums and applications.
As an artist, or creative technologist or whatever you might want to call it.
My life&amp;rsquo;s calling always has been to create, tinker, learn..
I love to explore for the sake of finding the small moments &amp;ldquo;the glitch in the matrix&amp;rdquo; or the &amp;ldquo;wrinkle in the fabric of time&amp;rdquo; to document the secrets of the universe that present themselves.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resume</title>
      <link>https://chrisried.xyz/resume/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2022 21:38:52 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chrisried.xyz/resume/</guid>
      <description>Experience Founder | CBayes Media Labs | Oct 2021 - Present In October 2021, started working on Web3 projects Ethereum / Tezos blockchain. Contracted with well-known angel investors and music industry professionals on projects as a consultant. Senior Data Scientist | Kythera Labs | Apr 2021 - Oct 2021 Worked on a team of 5 data scientists working with proprietary claims data to identify cost savings opportunities by providing demographic intelligence.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CC Framework Releases, Strange Attractors and Generating Color Palettes</title>
      <link>https://chrisried.xyz/newsletter/generative-arts-76/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chrisried.xyz/newsletter/generative-arts-76/</guid>
      <description>First published on Substack
Imperfection inspires invention, imagination, creativity. It stimulates. The more I feel imperfect, the more I feel alive. - Jhumpa Lahiri
First of all! Thanks for continuing to be great supporters in readership and I hope you are always finding something new and interesting to read or learn.
Programming Differential Growth Program amazing, complex, and chaotic patterns via differential growth. Differential growth creates a chaotic system that can be used to model biological processes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Doing Nothing, Creative Freedom and Airfoil - Tutorial</title>
      <link>https://chrisried.xyz/newsletter/generative-arts-75/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chrisried.xyz/newsletter/generative-arts-75/</guid>
      <description>First published on [Substack}(https://open.substack.com/pub/generative/p/doing-nothing-creative-freedom-and?r=58kr3&amp;amp;utm_campaign=post&amp;amp;utm_medium=web)
Creativity is the fragrance of freedom. - OSHO
Hello fellow readers and greetings to all who have recently come across this newsletter. I appreciate your support through reading this little newsletter in light of so many other interesting things out there.
So a few thoughts I’ve been thinking about recently …
Individualism is a complex concept with many facets and profound implications for our psyche. The freedom it offers is particularly cherished by artists and those displaying creativity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Your Brain On Art, Plotters, and Veoluz</title>
      <link>https://chrisried.xyz/newsletter/generative-arts-74/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chrisried.xyz/newsletter/generative-arts-74/</guid>
      <description>First published on Substack
Creativity is a continual surprise. - Ray Bradbury
Hello All,
Welcome all who have recently subscribed in the last couple weeks. I am sovery grateful that you are all excited about this little practice of ours called creative coding.
Also, I’ve been putting together a little Github document on content creators who are doing creative coding tutorials. This is an in progress but I hope you can check them out and find either software or projects that interest you to learn new things!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Artist as Inventor, Max Meets GL and Organ Pipe Physics</title>
      <link>https://chrisried.xyz/newsletter/generative-arts-73/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chrisried.xyz/newsletter/generative-arts-73/</guid>
      <description>This was first published on Substack
Creativity is an intelligent escape from the perceived limits. - SANDEEP KAKKAR
I recently finished reading &amp;ldquo;Artist as Inventor.&amp;rdquo; Although it&amp;rsquo;s an academic work that requires effort to digest, its arguments stand out. Primarily, it asserts that art has consistently advanced technology, suggesting a kinship rather than a division between the two. It also emphasizes the crucial role artists play in technology advancement through tool experimentation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Noisy SVGs, Dynamic Wearables, and 2024 Predictions</title>
      <link>https://chrisried.xyz/newsletter/generative-arts-72/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chrisried.xyz/newsletter/generative-arts-72/</guid>
      <description>First published on Substack
AS AN INNOVATOR, YOU NEED TO BE AWARE OF HOW TRADITIONS, HABITS AND BIAS CAN ACT AS BARRIERS TO ACCEPTING NEW IDEAS. - MAX MCKEOWN
Has been previously posted on Substack.
Happy Holidays,
We are just about to enter a new year! 😱😱😱
This year flew by much faster than expected, which in hindsight isn’t surprising.
It does always bring a time of reflection and goal setting**.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pixels as Code, Lindenmayer Systems, and Crumpled Paper</title>
      <link>https://chrisried.xyz/newsletter/generative-arts-71/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chrisried.xyz/newsletter/generative-arts-71/</guid>
      <description>First published on Substack
Creativity can impact some sort of CHANGE in the WORLD. But we must first embrace pure DIFFERENCES and work together for a common cause. - Henry Johnson Jr
Hi my Friends!
First of all I want to thank all of you! We’ve passed 2000 subscribers to this newsletter and I can only thank you all so much for taking the time to subscribe. You don’t know how much it means to know that you are excited about</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Variable Fonts, Neural Graphic Primitives and Flash-backs</title>
      <link>https://chrisried.xyz/newsletter/generative-arts-70/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chrisried.xyz/newsletter/generative-arts-70/</guid>
      <description>First published on Substack
Admiring a creative soul at work is almost as satisfying as making your own paintings. E.A. Bucchianeri
This weekend I was able to spend some time looking over some of the old Masters of Flash. These books were huge inspirations in my early teens to come to realize that computers were powerful enough to explore new worlds using code.
The web creatives of the day and it’s just nostalgic to flip through these.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Live Coding Quilts, OpenSCAD, and the Tale of the Subpixel Zoo</title>
      <link>https://chrisried.xyz/newsletter/generative-arts-69/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chrisried.xyz/newsletter/generative-arts-69/</guid>
      <description>First published on Substack
Developing the skill of creativity, like with any other skill, takes time. Do devote time to creativity. Honor its flow and its magic. Allow it to become your Life Force. Train Creativity daily. -Natasa Pantovic Nuit
Disclaimer: All in progress work.. just documenting the work here..
In my previous discussion, I shared my current artistic endeavors, which involves playing with 3D objects and creating generative abstract sculptures that I would like to 3D print.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Organic Architecture, Automation, and Poisson Flow</title>
      <link>https://chrisried.xyz/newsletter/generative-arts-68/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chrisried.xyz/newsletter/generative-arts-68/</guid>
      <description>First published on Substack
Very well then! I&amp;rsquo;ll write, write write. He let the words soak into his mind and displace all else. - Richard Matheson
Automation: Animation Engine for Creative Coding Automaton is an animation engine for creative coding. While you&amp;rsquo;re doing creative coding, doing time-based animation by code sometimes causes you so much pain. This project provides a framework and its GUI to connect your coding pieces with animations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Generative Coding</title>
      <link>https://chrisried.xyz/resources/generative-coding/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chrisried.xyz/resources/generative-coding/</guid>
      <description>Creative Coding Details Following are different creative coding frameworks that make up the majority of creative coding projects that are seen in technology throughout the internet, museums and other technological venues worldwide.
C++ Name Type Project Type URL Github Link Description Status Arnold Paid https://docs.arnoldrenderer.com/api/arnold-7.1.2.0/index.html Cinder Open Source https://libcinder.org/ CGAL JUCE https://juce.com/ Maximillian https://github.com/micknoise/Maximilian OpenFrameworks https://openframeworks.cc/ Ossia https://ossia.io/ Unreal Engine 2D,3D https://www.unrealengine.com/ Python Name Type Project Type URL Github Link Description Status BespokeSynth Open Source https://www.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Generative Music</title>
      <link>https://chrisried.xyz/resources/generative-music/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chrisried.xyz/resources/generative-music/</guid>
      <description>Creative Coding Details </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reading Deeply, Modeling 3D Patterns and SVG Paths</title>
      <link>https://chrisried.xyz/newsletter/generative-arts-67/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chrisried.xyz/newsletter/generative-arts-67/</guid>
      <description>Originally posted on Substack
Read deeply. Stay open. Continue to wonder. -Austin Kleon
Good morning friends!
I want to thank you for your continued support!
I want to make a few points on reading deeply and how it might relate in creative coding / generative art. We have past the apex of popularity when it comes to generative art. It will be a fascinating era of history in the future that will bring some interesting insights into understanding creativity and market forces.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Early Computer Art, Word Music, and Creative PowerPoint Programming</title>
      <link>https://chrisried.xyz/newsletter/generative-arts-66/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chrisried.xyz/newsletter/generative-arts-66/</guid>
      <description>Originally posted on Substack
I had no idea how creative ambition and life balance could coexist, because achieving balance seemed to imply being content, and didn&amp;rsquo;t contentment mean you were no longer hungry&amp;quot;? And if you lost your hunger, didn&amp;rsquo;t you one day wake up in the suburbs helicopter parenting a couple of kids or working at a soul sucking corporate job? You stopped making art. You stopped being passionate. You stopped being you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Javascript Game Engines, Very Low Frequencies, and Randomness</title>
      <link>https://chrisried.xyz/newsletter/generative-arts-65/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chrisried.xyz/newsletter/generative-arts-65/</guid>
      <description>Originally posted on Substack
#065 - Creative Coding / Generative Arts Weekly &amp;ldquo;Creativity is the art of connecting randomness, the harmony found in unexpected patterns, the beauty in the chaos. It&amp;rsquo;s our mind&amp;rsquo;s dance with the universe&amp;rsquo;s spontaneity.” - ChatGPT by the wisdom of humanity
My apologies for not sending out a newsletter in the past couple of weeks. I&amp;rsquo;ve been finishing up some master&amp;rsquo;s classes, and the work has been quite intense.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fungal Architectures, R As A Game Engine, and Photoresistors</title>
      <link>https://chrisried.xyz/newsletter/generative-arts-64/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chrisried.xyz/newsletter/generative-arts-64/</guid>
      <description>Originally posted on Substack
&amp;ldquo;Creativity is intelligence having fun.&amp;rdquo; - Albert Einstein
I am so floored and thankful to the 53 new subscribers and 2 paid subscribers since the last edition of the newspaper. I do try my best to bring interesting content that I’ve found interesting.
Who Am I? Jasia Reichardt was born in 1933 in Warsaw, Poland.
Reichardt began her career as an art critic, writing for publications such as the Times Literary Supplement, Studio International, and Art International.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spinning Flips, 3D Ceramics, and #GenArtCraft</title>
      <link>https://chrisried.xyz/newsletter/generative-arts-63/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chrisried.xyz/newsletter/generative-arts-63/</guid>
      <description>Originally posted on Substack
My mission in life is not merely to survive, but to thrive; and to do so with some passion, some compassion, some humor, and some style. - Maya Angelou
Thank you so much to the 41 new subscribers since the last newsletter. I am always so very thankful for the support that you all show by simply subscribing.
Up to… Some weeks just fly by so quickly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Audio Reactive Shaders, Prehistoric Midjourney, and Modular ChatGPT</title>
      <link>https://chrisried.xyz/newsletter/generative-arts-62/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chrisried.xyz/newsletter/generative-arts-62/</guid>
      <description>Originally posted on Substack
Creativity thrives where its roots are crowded. -Ozzie Zehner
Good Morning!
I&amp;rsquo;ve found that this is the best way for me to get inspiration. Unfortunately, I don&amp;rsquo;t have as much time as I&amp;rsquo;d like, but I think it&amp;rsquo;s all about finding balance. When I was a full-time artist, I had a difficult time with this, but when I have other things in my life that help drive me, that&amp;rsquo;s when I&amp;rsquo;m at my best.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AI Sculpting, Voronoi Fonts, and Tomorrow and Tomorrow</title>
      <link>https://chrisried.xyz/newsletter/generative-arts-61/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chrisried.xyz/newsletter/generative-arts-61/</guid>
      <description>Originally posted on [Substack](AI Sculpting, Voronoi Fonts, and Tomorrow and Tomorrow)
Creativity thrives where its roots are crowded. -Ozzie Zehner
Good morning friends!
I hope you all had a wonderful weekend!
Here are a few interesting links for you all to explore and discover. Right now I’ve been rather busy so I hope that you can find some
Who Am I? Last weeks image was Harold Cohen
Here is a great overview of his life and work!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Prophetic Art, ChatGPT Inside and Out, and The History of Shadows</title>
      <link>https://chrisried.xyz/newsletter/generative-arts-60/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chrisried.xyz/newsletter/generative-arts-60/</guid>
      <description>Originally posted on Substack
The nature of yearning is urgent so as to guarantee evolution, change. -Darryl Calkins
“We are the knights of a future realm.”
I’ve been wading through the libraries of the mind trying to grapple with the relationship of art and it’s prophetic nature. There appears to be a correlation that art has a predilection to predict the future of culture. It also tends to have gravitational pull on innovation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>10PRINT SVG, Visual Language Workshop, and Text to Music?</title>
      <link>https://chrisried.xyz/newsletter/generative-arts-59/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chrisried.xyz/newsletter/generative-arts-59/</guid>
      <description>Originally posted on Substack
It’s humbling that in the past 90 days, I’ve had subscribed readers from 75 different countries. In a world with so much content and other things to do, I do appreciate your interest in this passion of mine and I hope I can continue celebrating this practice with you all.
But to some of my weeks shenanigans:
So speaking of AI, I’ve been working with ChatGPT to develop catchy article titles to gain inspiration for a few posts I’d like to write this year.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weiwei, Evolving Alien Coral and Visualizing Science</title>
      <link>https://chrisried.xyz/newsletter/generative-arts-58/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chrisried.xyz/newsletter/generative-arts-58/</guid>
      <description>Originally posted on Substack
Art is a tool to set up new questions -Ai Weiwei
So last week, I started adding a new segment to experiment with, and I have a couple more in mind that I’d like to try over the future weeks. But why this “who am I?”
As some of my long-time subscribers have probably noticed, History is important to me. It brings context to both the old and the new.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Drawing Ideas, 3D CSS, and Immersive Art</title>
      <link>https://chrisried.xyz/newsletter/generative-arts-57/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chrisried.xyz/newsletter/generative-arts-57/</guid>
      <description>Originally posted on Substack
Great minds discuss ideas. Average minds discuss events. Small minds discuss people. - Henry Thomas Buckle
I want to say thank you so much to the subscribers that continue to sign up far! And thank you to the paid subscribers for your support that is so generous of you!
This week I’ve been thinking through various ways I can bring some interesting content into the mix.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Genuary 2023, Reflections, and Artificial Life</title>
      <link>https://chrisried.xyz/newsletter/generative-arts-56/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chrisried.xyz/newsletter/generative-arts-56/</guid>
      <description>Originally posted on Substack
The true secret to happiness lies in taking a genuine interest in all the details of daily life. -William Morris
A little over a year ago, I dedicated a year and my full-time work to generative/creative coding and thought I’d give a bit of an update. What went well, what I wished I could have done better, etc.
I aimed to do the following:
Interview more generative artists like Tyler Hobbs here… Outcome: I have done 0 of them since last year 😟.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Narrative Scripting, Live Coding, and Happy Holidays!</title>
      <link>https://chrisried.xyz/newsletter/generative-arts-55/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chrisried.xyz/newsletter/generative-arts-55/</guid>
      <description>Originally posted on Substack
Every mistake is a new style. -Michael Meade
Happy Holidays!
I hope you find time to appreciate the little things in life.
It is a time of stress, family, loneliness, and remembering those we lost.
So be kind to yourself, and find ways to appreciate the chaos..
May that be a little piece of code to obsess about, a quote to ponder, a walk in nature to absorb the color, smells, emotions, or simply the sound of the cold wind tickling your inner ear.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Algorists, Metaballs and Shader Prototyping</title>
      <link>https://chrisried.xyz/newsletter/generative-arts-53/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chrisried.xyz/newsletter/generative-arts-53/</guid>
      <description>Originally posted on Substack
if(creation &amp;amp;&amp;amp; object of art &amp;amp;&amp;amp; algorithm &amp;amp;&amp;amp; one’s own algorithm) { include * an algorist* } else if(!creation &amp;amp;&amp;amp; !object of art &amp;amp;&amp;amp; !algorithm &amp;amp;&amp;amp; !one’s own algorithm) { exclude not an algorist }
The above statement was the manifesto coined by J. P. Herbert and the mantra of The Algorists; a group formed in 1995 at SIGGRAPH which included (Roman Verostko, Jean-Pierre Hébert, and Ken Musgrave).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blockchain Analytics</title>
      <link>https://chrisried.xyz/posts/blockchain-landscape-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chrisried.xyz/posts/blockchain-landscape-2022/</guid>
      <description>The following post provides some context around the many many different technologies that are currently out there in the blockchain space. Much of these are changing on a monthly basis with new things coming out all the time. So I thought it might be good to have a document that tries to compile what this landscape currently looks like in 2022.
Value Store Blockchain Bitcoin - open source payment network Blockchains (Multipurpose) Ethereum The current most popular Solana Currently one of the rising stars in the space, there are many interesting projects that are currently being worked on.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Create Generative Art</title>
      <link>https://chrisried.xyz/posts/2022-10-26-how-to-make-generative-art/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chrisried.xyz/posts/2022-10-26-how-to-make-generative-art/</guid>
      <description>Following are 10 ways how to start learning how to make generative art.
Learn how to use a framework or software for generative art. There are a number of different ways to do this. Here is a mindmap as a guide. I&amp;rsquo;d suggest just looking at them and start searching for them.
Take a few art classes There are plenty of places online such as Domestika or Skillshare that will help you find inspiration, and open your mind to new ideas of expression.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Web3 Landscape (2022)</title>
      <link>https://chrisried.xyz/posts/web3-landscape-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chrisried.xyz/posts/web3-landscape-2022/</guid>
      <description>First of all, this continues to change and will be extremely interesting to work with over the next number of years. There are a number of interesting use cases ad much is about rethinking the web infrastructure.
Wallets Metamask - Muun Security Coinbase - A marketplace L2 Blockchain Polygon - Finance Digital Collectables (NFTs) OpenSea - First and currently the foremost NFT platform supporting the ethereum and L2 Polygon chains </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FFMPEG Video Art, Generative Audio and Ken Perlin</title>
      <link>https://chrisried.xyz/newsletter/generative-arts-51/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chrisried.xyz/newsletter/generative-arts-51/</guid>
      <description>Originally posted on Substack
Silence creates space for content to appear. -J.R. Rim
Video Art with FFMPEG {{ youtube nobWeGycSe8 }}
One of the many tools we use to describe motion is in a sequence of images or videos. We love them and use them for our work as it adds yet another dimension to the images. The following few selections all use FFMPEG an open source tool to convert video from different formats in the command line or through a programming language.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hallucinating Art Models, Sound Design in Python, and a little Canvas</title>
      <link>https://chrisried.xyz/newsletter/generative-arts-50/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chrisried.xyz/newsletter/generative-arts-50/</guid>
      <description>Originally posted on Substack
Make things happen, Don&amp;rsquo;t let things happen to you. -Syed Sharukh
Hello creatives!
I’ve been spending quite a bit of time learning a bunch of technologies in the last year to continue stepping up the various skills needed to really try what I have in my mind. Much of it has to do with in real life materials but using generative techniques to really drive it and so I hope to share in the future.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lined Up Imperfectly</title>
      <link>https://chrisried.xyz/projects/lined-up-imperfectly/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chrisried.xyz/projects/lined-up-imperfectly/</guid>
      <description>The collection has clothlike qualities but still lies in fundamental structures as we experiment and try to understand the intersection between the rigid and fluid.
#1
#2
#3
#4</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stable Diffusion, Biologically Augmented Bespoke Pieces and Surrealism</title>
      <link>https://chrisried.xyz/newsletter/generative-arts-48/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chrisried.xyz/newsletter/generative-arts-48/</guid>
      <description>Originally posted on Substack
The detail is everything -Vladimir Nabokov
As much as the last year has been at a slower pace of releasing this newsletter. I do want to get back into the habit of highlighting the wonderful world of generative and creative coding arts on a more regular basis so I hope you have been able to enjoy the work.
Few Thoughts on AI Art You will find that much of this weeks highlights do look at the Stable Diffusion model that has been released in the past 2 weeks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The &#34;War of Art&#34; and Painting Poetry</title>
      <link>https://chrisried.xyz/newsletter/generative-arts-49/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chrisried.xyz/newsletter/generative-arts-49/</guid>
      <description>Originally posted on Substack
It is a commonplace among artists and children at play that they&amp;rsquo;re not aware of time or solitude while they&amp;rsquo;re chasing their vision. The hours fly. - Steven Pressfield
I’ve been reading the book “The War of Art” by Steven Pressfield and have found a number of quotes that have resonated with me quite a bit over the last year. Specifically when it comes to knowing how to simple continue.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Morphing Spheres and Phyllotactic Spirals</title>
      <link>https://chrisried.xyz/newsletter/generative-arts-47/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chrisried.xyz/newsletter/generative-arts-47/</guid>
      <description>Originally posted on Substack
It&amp;rsquo;s a great time to be a creator. Trust your creativity. -Ron Howard
Reflecting on the past year..
{{ youtube OFI1FJcGLeM }}
The Art of John Edmark What do plants know about numbers? A certain spiral pattern commonly seen in sunflowers, pinecones, and many species of cacti contains some surprising numerical properties. In this brisk talk, Paul Dancstep investigates this pattern through several kinetic sculptures by artist John Edmark.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Generative 3D Art Tools and Inspirations</title>
      <link>https://chrisried.xyz/newsletter/generative-arts-46/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chrisried.xyz/newsletter/generative-arts-46/</guid>
      <description>Originally posted on Substack
“If you&amp;rsquo;re not prepared to be wrong, you&amp;rsquo;ll never come up with anything original.” -Ken Robinson
I’ve had a number of requests and personal interest where 3D imagery is used to create generative art. So I hope that this is beneficial.
Generative art can be done in almost every application. You will find that it can be done in Photoshop, using code, using simply code in the browser, or just by hand as one of my fellow generative artists (Dan Gries) has done.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Algoraves, Weird AI Art, and Generative Tools</title>
      <link>https://chrisried.xyz/newsletter/generative-arts-45/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chrisried.xyz/newsletter/generative-arts-45/</guid>
      <description>Originally posted on Substack
If it doesn’t fit comfortably within your heart, let it go. - Toni Sorenson
Well its been a little over a month since the last newsletter has gone out. There are just too many things to get done in a day.
Also, I have been working at making the links from the last 40+ newsletters in one place so that they are more accessible. Right now they are just a Markdown page but hopefully will give this a little more structure as well.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Generative Music, Lambda Calculus, and GLSL in Blender</title>
      <link>https://chrisried.xyz/newsletter/generative-arts-44/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chrisried.xyz/newsletter/generative-arts-44/</guid>
      <description>Originally posted on Substack
The job of the artist is always to deepen the mystery -Francis Bacon
Hello Friends,
It’s been another couple weeks since the last edition has gone out. I’ve been spending time on my own artwork, gathering books and inspirations along with traveling and working on another project involving blockchains.
Hope you enjoy!
Chris Ried
📰 Happenings Eyeo Festival - June 14 - 17, 2022 School of Poetic Computation - Multiple Courses Anderson Ranch Art Center - Multiple Classes Processing and Laser: Creative Code to Wood Panel - June 27 - July 1, 2022 Drawing with Machines - July 18 - 22, 2022 📸 Generative Meet Vera Monar, the 98-Year-Old Generative Art Pioneer Who Is Enjoying New Relevance at the Venice Bienniale “For me, arriving in Paris was happiness,” Molnár told me of her emigration to the French capital in 1947 with François Molnar, who would become her husband.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Requiem of Creativity</title>
      <link>https://chrisried.xyz/newsletter/generative-arts-43/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chrisried.xyz/newsletter/generative-arts-43/</guid>
      <description>Originally posted on Substack
Practice any art, music, singing, dancing, acting, drawing, painting, sculpting, poetry, fiction, essays, reportage, no matter how well or badly, not to get money and fame, but to experience becoming, to find out what’s inside of you, to make your soul grow. Seriously! I mean starting right now, do art and do it for the rest of your lives. - Kurt Vonnegut
The quote above is so powerful that I really don’t think there is much more to be said.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Granular Blocks of Play</title>
      <link>https://chrisried.xyz/projects/granular-blocks-of-play/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chrisried.xyz/projects/granular-blocks-of-play/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been experimenting with creating blocks or rectangles with various color gradients using the pixelated variations. It is by far a most satisfying when you can then take it and use sin waves to give the edges a little more interesting flow.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Design Systems, Embroidered Sculptures and Isometric Projections</title>
      <link>https://chrisried.xyz/newsletter/generative-arts-43/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chrisried.xyz/newsletter/generative-arts-43/</guid>
      <description>Originally posted on Substack
&amp;ldquo;Don’t worry if people think you’re crazy. You are crazy. You have that kind of intoxicating insanity that lets other people dream outside of the lines and become who they’re destined to be.&amp;rdquo; - Jennifer Elisabeth
I would love to see some critique in the generative arts space&amp;hellip;
But a traditional art critic would give us a perspective of how it fits into the tapestry of art history and the emerging trends that occur within the community.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Web Art History, Coding in Blender and Coding Raytracing on a Calculator</title>
      <link>https://chrisried.xyz/newsletter/generative-arts-41/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chrisried.xyz/newsletter/generative-arts-41/</guid>
      <description>Originally posted on Substack
&amp;ldquo;Art enables us to find ourselves and lose ourselves at the same time.&amp;rdquo; - Thomas Merton
Good Evening Readers!
It&amp;rsquo;s been a rather interesting couple of months adjusting to full-time work at home and trying to really give a thorough think on what it means to make art, and what does generative art stand for in the context of today. Many questions that have been on my mind are:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2022 Predictions, Genuary 2022 and SYMAP</title>
      <link>https://chrisried.xyz/newsletter/generative-arts-40/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chrisried.xyz/newsletter/generative-arts-40/</guid>
      <description>Originally posted on Substack
“Success is not final, failure is not fatal: it is the courage to continue that counts.” - Winston Churchill
And 2022 is here&amp;hellip;
it&amp;rsquo;s truly remarkable how quickly time has gone and continues to go. This time last year, generative art was a small niche group of enthusiasts who appreciate the art form. Now.. well it&amp;rsquo;s become quite an interesting spectacle and will be interesting to see how it continues to play over the next couple of years.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Celestial Collisions</title>
      <link>https://chrisried.xyz/projects/celestial-collisions/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chrisried.xyz/projects/celestial-collisions/</guid>
      <description>The following project spanned across 800 editions that were released on FXHash in Dec 2021. Conceptually, this was a meditation on scale and collision. Scale is intuitively misunderstood by humans. We have a poor judgement how big, or how small things really are as we do not have a reference of comparison.
It may be due to the fact that these scales are recent discoveries.
We have seen stars for millenium, but we have not had a good understanding at their size until&amp;hellip; The same goes for really small items.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Constructivist Art, Some Interesting Reads and Painting Catapults</title>
      <link>https://chrisried.xyz/newsletter/generative-arts-39/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chrisried.xyz/newsletter/generative-arts-39/</guid>
      <description>Originally posted on Substack
Never stop dreaming.. - Roy T. Bennett
Good morning my friends!
I hope you are finding amazing inspiration in the interesting stuff that you have been working on.
First up: Content these days take longer to curate because its a niche space so I&amp;rsquo;d love for anyone to send me interesting generative/ creative works that they have created or inspired by.
I&amp;rsquo;ve also been spending a good deal of time trying a bunch different things that I have been releasing fewer newsletters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Painting Robots, Domain Shifting And Creating an Inviting Space in Generative Art</title>
      <link>https://chrisried.xyz/newsletter/generative-arts-38/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chrisried.xyz/newsletter/generative-arts-38/</guid>
      <description>Originally posted on Substack
Never stop dreaming.. - Roy T. Bennett
First of all, I can&amp;rsquo;t thank you enough for your participation on Twitter in recommending the many wonderful women in the generative space. I think it&amp;rsquo;s amazing to see so much talent and creativity in the space. I&amp;rsquo;ll highlight over the next number of newsletters.
Creating An Inviting Space in Generative Art I think it is important that we encourage a depth of perspective that comes we celebrate inclusion.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Asemic Palimpsest</title>
      <link>https://chrisried.xyz/projects/asemic-palimpsest/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chrisried.xyz/projects/asemic-palimpsest/</guid>
      <description>Fonts, texts and pens have always been a part of who I am. Much of my growing up years</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Geometric Meditations</title>
      <link>https://chrisried.xyz/projects/geometric-meditations/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chrisried.xyz/projects/geometric-meditations/</guid>
      <description>These are some of my favorite things.. the grid and then building an image inside each of the grids has a sense of satisfaction to me. I am not quite sure what that is, but it is quite swell.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In the Light</title>
      <link>https://chrisried.xyz/projects/in-the-light/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chrisried.xyz/projects/in-the-light/</guid>
      <description>Much of my work will include elements of nature. Simply because I am obsessed by it and it&amp;rsquo;s where I find the most inspiration and peace in life.
In the light is a bit of a play toward that..</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Marfa, Subdivision and Runtime Patching</title>
      <link>https://chrisried.xyz/newsletter/generative-arts-37/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chrisried.xyz/newsletter/generative-arts-37/</guid>
      <description>Originally posted on Substack
&amp;ldquo;Change the way you look at things and the things you look at change.&amp;rdquo; - Wayne W. Dyer
So this weekend I had the amazing opportunity to make it to Marfa Texas for the inaugural Artblocks weekend which was such a treat.
I was able to meet a bunch of genart inspirations; Caleb Ogg (iso.hedron), Aaron Penne (aaron_penne), Tyler Hobbs (tylerxhobbs), Kesean (keseantx), Stefan Contiero (stefan_contiero), Dimitri Cherniak (dmitricherniak) to name a few which was a special treat.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dark City</title>
      <link>https://chrisried.xyz/projects/dark-city/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chrisried.xyz/projects/dark-city/</guid>
      <description>This just reminds me of cities after dark and the lighting that just doesn&amp;rsquo;t quite have a comfortable effect.
These pieces were created to be NFTs on the Tezos blockchain. You can view it on Objkt
#1
#2
#3
#4
#5
#6
#7
#8
#9
#10
#11
#12</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Like The Emperors Robe</title>
      <link>https://chrisried.xyz/projects/emperors-robe/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chrisried.xyz/projects/emperors-robe/</guid>
      <description>The following generative piece appears like the robe of an emperor. When looking closely, you will find that each square is unique as it builds a web of fabric. You can find the pieces on Objkt</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interlocking Cable Ties, Generative NFTs, Mathematical Optimization Art</title>
      <link>https://chrisried.xyz/newsletter/generative-arts-34/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chrisried.xyz/newsletter/generative-arts-34/</guid>
      <description>Originally posted on Substack
&amp;ldquo;The most beautiful thing we can experience is the mysterious. It is the source of all true art and all science. He to whom this emotion is a stranger, who can no longer pause to wonder and stand rapt in awe, is as good as dead: his eyes are closed.&amp;rdquo; - Albert Einstein
Hello Friends,
This week has been fascinating on multiple fronts in the generative art space.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nodi3D, Machines Making Art, and Eigenvectors</title>
      <link>https://chrisried.xyz/newsletter/generative-arts-35/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chrisried.xyz/newsletter/generative-arts-35/</guid>
      <description>Originally posted on Substack
&amp;ldquo;A blank canvas&amp;hellip;has unlimited possibilities.&amp;rdquo; - Stephanie Perkins
Good Evening Folks or Happy Friday!
I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on multiple small projects and this above was supposed to be a simple infographic of the most popular frameworks. However it has become an all weekend event on Twitter which was a great community effort. Being that there has been so much interest, I though this will be a great opportunity to move the wireframe version above into an interactive graph which I do look forward to finishing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Everyday Luxury in Nines</title>
      <link>https://chrisried.xyz/projects/everything-luxury-in-nines/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chrisried.xyz/projects/everything-luxury-in-nines/</guid>
      <description>The following generative piece emphasizes a set of 9 illusions all telling a different story. In history, 9 has been signified as a number of divine completeness. However completeness is usually clean and luxuriant, here the image contrasts the everyday messiness of life. Each element of 9 tells a familiar but different story. Can you find yours?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>End of Summer Reign</title>
      <link>https://chrisried.xyz/projects/end-of-summer-reign/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chrisried.xyz/projects/end-of-summer-reign/</guid>
      <description>The following generative piece imagines the end of summer. These can be found on Objkt</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Turning Winters</title>
      <link>https://chrisried.xyz/projects/turning-winters/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chrisried.xyz/projects/turning-winters/</guid>
      <description>The following layered spiral contemplation</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In Summer and Splashpads</title>
      <link>https://chrisried.xyz/projects/in-summer-and-splashpads/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chrisried.xyz/projects/in-summer-and-splashpads/</guid>
      <description>Its at the end of summer and it brings happiness to all! When looking closer every shape is made up of small ovals that are layered in a very specific pattern. Some of the ovals are spread out more, others are different shades, transparent and variations of each color.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cubic Spirals</title>
      <link>https://chrisried.xyz/projects/cubic-spirals/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chrisried.xyz/projects/cubic-spirals/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Surrealism</title>
      <link>https://chrisried.xyz/projects/surrealism/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chrisried.xyz/projects/surrealism/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zhufu</title>
      <link>https://chrisried.xyz/projects/zhufu/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chrisried.xyz/projects/zhufu/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deceptively Simple</title>
      <link>https://chrisried.xyz/projects/deceptively-simple/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chrisried.xyz/projects/deceptively-simple/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hypnotic Stasis</title>
      <link>https://chrisried.xyz/projects/hypnotic-stasis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chrisried.xyz/projects/hypnotic-stasis/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fourier Transforms, Glitch Monsters, Digital Art Displays</title>
      <link>https://chrisried.xyz/newsletter/generative-arts-33/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chrisried.xyz/newsletter/generative-arts-33/</guid>
      <description>Originally posted on Substack
&amp;ldquo;Don’t worry if people think you’re crazy. You are crazy. You have that kind of intoxicating insanity that lets other people dream outside of the lines and become who they’re destined to be.&amp;rdquo; - Jennifer Elisabeth
Hello friends!
I hope you all have been having great weeks full of inspiration. I know that I am spotty right now with the newsletter. There are a number of things going on (two jobs mainly) which I hope will pass in the next couple of months.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alien Dreams, Generating MIDI, and Drawing with Oceans</title>
      <link>https://chrisried.xyz/newsletter/generative-arts-32/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chrisried.xyz/newsletter/generative-arts-32/</guid>
      <description>Originally posted on Substack
&amp;ldquo;To be an artist means never to avert one&amp;rsquo;s eyes.&amp;rdquo; - Akira Kurosawa
Paying attention to detail is one of the hidden secrets of any artist.
It provides them the ability the &amp;ldquo;see&amp;rdquo; and interpret their surroundings or emotions of any subject in ways the viewer has yet to understand.
La Crau w/ Peach Trees - Van Gogh
Take, for instance, the following painting by Van Gogh.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Triangular Explosions</title>
      <link>https://chrisried.xyz/projects/triangular-explosions/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chrisried.xyz/projects/triangular-explosions/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Conceptual Art, Fear, and Generative Synthesis</title>
      <link>https://chrisried.xyz/newsletter/generative-arts-31/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chrisried.xyz/newsletter/generative-arts-31/</guid>
      <description>Originally posted on Substack
I&amp;rsquo;ve been reading through the book &amp;ldquo;Art &amp;amp; Fear&amp;rdquo; by David Bayles and Ted Orland. I thought I might share a few passages that I highlighted. that are good nuggets about pursuing art and the insecurities that come with it.
The function of the overwhelming majority of your artwork is simply to teach you how to make the small fraction of your artwork that soars. One of the basic and difficult lessons every artist must learn is that even the failed pieces are essential.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Locusts Armageddon</title>
      <link>https://chrisried.xyz/projects/locusts-armageddon/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chrisried.xyz/projects/locusts-armageddon/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Imprints of a Dandilion</title>
      <link>https://chrisried.xyz/projects/imprints-of-a-dandilion/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chrisried.xyz/projects/imprints-of-a-dandilion/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Psychadelic Squares</title>
      <link>https://chrisried.xyz/projects/psychadelic-squares/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chrisried.xyz/projects/psychadelic-squares/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bonsai Trees, Color History and Depth Estimation</title>
      <link>https://chrisried.xyz/newsletter/generative-arts-29/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chrisried.xyz/newsletter/generative-arts-29/</guid>
      <description>Originally posted on Substack
&amp;ldquo;The absence of limitations is the enemy of art.&amp;rdquo; - Orson Welles
The discipline of trimming and waiting, the bonsai master takes the medium of the tree and molds it using wire as a way to encourage the shape of growth. Throughout the years he cuts, and prunes, sheers and replants and cuts some more.
Once in a while he moves the tree to a new pot, sifting through the roots system looking for only the living and then places the bonsai back into position.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Primitive Prophesy</title>
      <link>https://chrisried.xyz/projects/primitive-prophesy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chrisried.xyz/projects/primitive-prophesy/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What makes a good generative agent?</title>
      <link>https://chrisried.xyz/newsletter/generative-arts-28/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chrisried.xyz/newsletter/generative-arts-28/</guid>
      <description>Originally posted on Substack
&amp;ldquo;The Artist always has the masters in his eyes.&amp;rdquo; - Ralph Waldo Emerson
What makes a good generative agent? It&amp;rsquo;s an interesting question, that I will scratch but the surface. However, I’ve gathered a list of general considerations from my observations of the generative arts. My intent is to discover and explore.
Some of this comes from the pursuit of understanding… in an ironic way. For one, It is the pursuit which help build an eye for the different, and aesthetically pleasing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cistercian Numerals, 3D Models, and Perfect Loops</title>
      <link>https://chrisried.xyz/newsletter/generative-arts-27/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chrisried.xyz/newsletter/generative-arts-27/</guid>
      <description>Originally posted on Substack
&amp;ldquo;The Artist always has the masters in his eyes.&amp;rdquo; - Ralph Waldo Emerson
Good Evening Friends!
I&amp;rsquo;ve been busy starting a new job and trying to replatform as a way to ensure that the newsletter is in a format that can be accessible and more automated for me. Right now I have been using Substack, however I am wanting to create great content, and automate as much as possible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Experiments In Chaos</title>
      <link>https://chrisried.xyz/projects/experiments-in-chaos/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chrisried.xyz/projects/experiments-in-chaos/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Futuristic Generative Art, Ferrofluids and Simulations</title>
      <link>https://chrisried.xyz/newsletter/generative-arts-26/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chrisried.xyz/newsletter/generative-arts-26/</guid>
      <description>Originally posted on Substack
&amp;ldquo;An artist&amp;rsquo;s concern is to capture beauty wherever he finds it.&amp;rdquo; - Kazuo Ishiguro
What does generative art look like in the future?
As much as I enjoy investigating the path that the discipline of generative art has taken in the past 60+ years; I also have been thinking about what the future may hold in this space.
So what I am going throw out there has yet to be fully thought through.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From Generative Systems to Generative Aesthetics</title>
      <link>https://chrisried.xyz/newsletter/generative-arts-24/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chrisried.xyz/newsletter/generative-arts-24/</guid>
      <description>Originally posted on Substack
&amp;ldquo;Any great art work … revives and readapts time and space, and the measure of its success is the extent to which it makes you an inhabitant of that world - the extent to which it invites you in and lets you breathe its strange, special air.&amp;rdquo; - Leonard Bernstein
Generative Systems to Generative Aesthetics All of my life, art has been a piece of my existence.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Random Machines, Creative Rust, Blurred Boundaries</title>
      <link>https://chrisried.xyz/newsletter/generative-arts-25/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chrisried.xyz/newsletter/generative-arts-25/</guid>
      <description>Originally posted on Substack
&amp;ldquo;I became an artist because I wanted to be an active participant in the conversation about art.&amp;rdquo; - Kamand Kojouri
Alrighty, well I wanted to complete a piece on randomness called the &amp;ldquo;Ode to Randomness&amp;rdquo; as there is so much to be written and techniques in which randomness is so important to the work of generative artists. But I&amp;rsquo;ll get it out soon enough. Instead; here is an interesting usage of randomness.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Generative Poetry, Archimedian Solids and Dextro</title>
      <link>https://chrisried.xyz/newsletter/generative-arts-23/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chrisried.xyz/newsletter/generative-arts-23/</guid>
      <description>Originally posted on Substack
&amp;ldquo;At the end of your creative adventure, you have a souvenir—something that you made, something to remind you forever of your brief but transformative encounter with inspiration&amp;rdquo; - Elizabeth Gilbert
The last couple of weeks have been quite eventful. I&amp;rsquo;ve taken a new job and there has been much transitioning that has occurred to get everything completed.
That being said, my work on aggregating / discovering the history of generative art has been progressing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Generative Past, Flowing Type and Micobe Ecosystems</title>
      <link>https://chrisried.xyz/newsletter/generative-arts-22/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chrisried.xyz/newsletter/generative-arts-22/</guid>
      <description>Originally posted on Substack
“The programmer, like the poet, works only slightly removed from pure thought-stuff. He builds his castles in the air, from the air, creating by the exertion of the imagination.” - Frederick Brooks
Quick update: Well its been 6 months of almost weekly newsletters and I am so excited of how much content and interest (~500 Substack subscribes) there has been! I&amp;rsquo;ve loved the interactions I&amp;rsquo;ve had with you all and will hope to continue to do so!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pipelines</title>
      <link>https://chrisried.xyz/projects/pipelines/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chrisried.xyz/projects/pipelines/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alda, Generative Music in Clojure, Generative Pixel Art</title>
      <link>https://chrisried.xyz/newsletter/generative-arts-21/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chrisried.xyz/newsletter/generative-arts-21/</guid>
      <description>Originally posted on Substack
&amp;ldquo;Creativity is the fragrance of individual freedom.&amp;rdquo; - Osho
Hello friends!
I know that I generally release on Saturday for the week but we had family and work which led to not having as much time this weekend to ensure that I finish editing the video done in time for the next release.
And it is here! My conversation with Dave Yarwood led us down some very interesting conversations on the idea of generative music and how one might go around using a system such as Alda to create &amp;ldquo;generative music.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Square and Rectangular</title>
      <link>https://chrisried.xyz/projects/square-and-rectangular/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chrisried.xyz/projects/square-and-rectangular/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thoughts on NFTs, Algo-music and Processes</title>
      <link>https://chrisried.xyz/newsletter/generative-arts-20/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chrisried.xyz/newsletter/generative-arts-20/</guid>
      <description>Originally posted on Substack
&amp;ldquo;Creativity is a synthesis of two qualities: imagination and concreteness.&amp;rdquo; - Pearl Zhu
As NFTs are all the rage, I thought I might lay out my thoughts and maybe inspire more conversation and thoughts. So I&amp;rsquo;ve intended this to be considered in small chunks.
I love the fact that the non-centralized infrastructure brings transparency to the masses. I don&amp;rsquo;t like the idea that we could be speeding up the process of CO2 shot into the environment due to additional electrical consumption of the blockchains.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ink Streams, Glitch Aesthetics and Generative Typography</title>
      <link>https://chrisried.xyz/newsletter/generative-arts-19/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chrisried.xyz/newsletter/generative-arts-19/</guid>
      <description>Originally posted on Substack
&amp;ldquo;Set your imagination free and do your best to keep up with it.&amp;rdquo; - A.R. Fagundes
Another week has come and gone.
I am currently working on an essay trying to historically outline the world of generative art since the 1960s. I&amp;rsquo;d like to really trace the thread back to compile a little history just because I love origin stories and I also highlight our &amp;ldquo;ancestors&amp;rdquo; of the generative arts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Photons and Light Sources</title>
      <link>https://chrisried.xyz/projects/photons-and-light-sources/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chrisried.xyz/projects/photons-and-light-sources/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dinos In Birthday Hats</title>
      <link>https://chrisried.xyz/projects/dinos-in-birthday-hats/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chrisried.xyz/projects/dinos-in-birthday-hats/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simplified Containment</title>
      <link>https://chrisried.xyz/projects/simplified-containment/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chrisried.xyz/projects/simplified-containment/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spiraling Arcs, Crypto Art, and Voronoi in Blender</title>
      <link>https://chrisried.xyz/newsletter/generative-arts-18/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chrisried.xyz/newsletter/generative-arts-18/</guid>
      <description>Originally posted on Substack
&amp;ldquo;Set your imagination free and do your best to keep up with it.&amp;rdquo; - A.R. Fagundes
Another week has come and gone.
I am currently working on an essay trying to historically outline the world of generative art since the 1960s. I&amp;rsquo;d like to really trace the thread back to compile a little history just because I love origin stories and I also highlight our &amp;ldquo;ancestors&amp;rdquo; of the generative arts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Autonomous Artistry and the Physical</title>
      <link>https://chrisried.xyz/newsletter/generative-arts-17/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chrisried.xyz/newsletter/generative-arts-17/</guid>
      <description>Originally posted on Substack
“A work of art which did not begin in emotion is not art.&amp;quot; ― Paul Cezanne
One of the things that I hope we continue to remember as &amp;ldquo;autonomous art&amp;rdquo; (i.e. currently GANs and generative artistic systems) becomes more apparent in the coming decade. Let&amp;rsquo;s not forget what makes art and the aesthetic beautiful. the process and the relationship one has with a piece of art.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Minimum Distance between a Point and a Line</title>
      <link>https://chrisried.xyz/posts/2021-02-20-minimum-distance-point-line/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chrisried.xyz/posts/2021-02-20-minimum-distance-point-line/</guid>
      <description>This has been transcribed from an earlier post of the internet. I felt as though it might be good to rewrite and also include some of the information that is part of the
This note describes the technique and gives the solution to finding the shortest distance from a point to a line or line segment. The equation of a line defined through two points \(P_1\) \((x1,y1)\) and \(P_2\) \((x2,y2)\) is</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Procedural Nodes, Self Organizing Textures, and Tyler Hobbs</title>
      <link>https://chrisried.xyz/newsletter/generative-arts-16/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chrisried.xyz/newsletter/generative-arts-16/</guid>
      <description>Originally posted on Substack
&amp;ldquo;If little else, the brain is an educational toy.&amp;rdquo; - Tom Robbins
Well, there is about 6 hours worth of learnable content that I&amp;rsquo;ve attached this week. Most of it I&amp;rsquo;ve been able to race through.
Tyler Hobbs Interview Being the first interview I&amp;rsquo;ve done this way. I am a little overwhelmed and self conscience but I decided that the beauty of generative is that sometimes the mistakes are just part of the output and should be kept.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Generative Art and R</title>
      <link>https://chrisried.xyz/newsletter/generative-arts-15/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chrisried.xyz/newsletter/generative-arts-15/</guid>
      <description>Originally posted on Substack
Art is the imposing of a pattern on experience, and our aesthetic enjoyment is recognition of the pattern.&amp;quot; - Alfred North Whitehead
R and Generative Art How do you like to see tools used for different things?
I enjoy seeing a tool used for something entirely different.
Take Excel, for example, it is a complicated calculator with a bunch of functions used for managing portfolios, budgeting, forecasting, to personal databases as the normal use case of Excel.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Experimenting With Fuzzy Circles</title>
      <link>https://chrisried.xyz/projects/experimenting-with-fuzzy-circles/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chrisried.xyz/projects/experimenting-with-fuzzy-circles/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fine Art, Daily Code Sketches and Leaf Venation</title>
      <link>https://chrisried.xyz/newsletter/generative-arts-12/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chrisried.xyz/newsletter/generative-arts-12/</guid>
      <description>Originally posted on Substack
&amp;ldquo;Vulnerability is the birthplace of innovation, creativity and change.&amp;rdquo; - Brene Brown
Happy Weekend Friends!
Its been a week. The people of the United States have much to consider for the future. It&amp;rsquo;s only through thoughtful debate and understanding on all sides in which we need to hash out our differences with patience, respect, kindness and vulnerability.
Otherwise it is our animalistic nature that will take its course.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fine Art, Daily Code Sketches and Leaf Venation</title>
      <link>https://chrisried.xyz/newsletter/generative-arts-12/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chrisried.xyz/newsletter/generative-arts-12/</guid>
      <description>Originally posted on Substack
&amp;ldquo;Create with the heart; build with the mind.&amp;rdquo; - Criss Jami
Good Morning!
I&amp;rsquo;ve been wondering, &amp;ldquo;What is creativity and where does it come from?&amp;rdquo; Are we wired with certain default, &amp;ldquo;inspirations&amp;rdquo; of ideas that generate the corpus we have come up with today? I think of Carl Jung&amp;rsquo;s story archetypes and it would seem that there is evidence for a collective conscience.
Yet, we still need to ask, are there entirely new ideas that have never been thought or created?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Whispering Wisps</title>
      <link>https://chrisried.xyz/projects/whispering-sisps/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chrisried.xyz/projects/whispering-sisps/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2021 has Come!</title>
      <link>https://chrisried.xyz/newsletter/generative-arts-11/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chrisried.xyz/newsletter/generative-arts-11/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;Creativity is the brain&amp;rsquo;s invisible muscle &amp;ndash; that when used and excercised routinely &amp;ndash; becomes better and stronger.&amp;rdquo; - Ashley Ormon
This is an abbreviated version of the newsletter to update last week. Due to the holidays, I haven&amp;rsquo;t finished the output in time for you to enjoy. But we will be back to normal next week.
But first, we have an announcement&amp;hellip;. 🥁
We have a winner!!!
Daryl from Manitoba has won the giveaway!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Can we use Simplex Noise to Generate Music?</title>
      <link>https://chrisried.xyz/newsletter/generative-arts-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chrisried.xyz/newsletter/generative-arts-10/</guid>
      <description>Originally posted on Substack
Life is full of beauty. Notice it. Notice the bumble bee, the small child, and the smiling faces. Smell the rain, and feel the wind. Live your life to the fullest potential, and fight for your dreams. - Ashley Smith
Good Morning Friends,
I have to say that this is going out a little later than usual but I think you will find some of the articles today to be much more in the details around simplex noise and the like but not all.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Would Picasso Use Code to Generate Art?</title>
      <link>https://chrisried.xyz/newsletter/generative-arts-9/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chrisried.xyz/newsletter/generative-arts-9/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;Art is not what you see, but what you make others see.&amp;rdquo; - Edgar Degas
The soul of art is depicted in the quote so well. Art is&amp;hellip; a little hard to pin down with words but it isn&amp;rsquo;t just simply the act of transcribing from the physical world to paper.
So what is it?
We do know it is important to us. We dedicate entire buildings to the collection of art, we have art stores, art classes, and even entire markets that deal in it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cloud Fractals, Blooms, and Spinning Parametrics</title>
      <link>https://chrisried.xyz/newsletter/generative-arts-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chrisried.xyz/newsletter/generative-arts-8/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;The noblest pleasure is the joy of understanding.&amp;rdquo; - Leonardo da Vinci
Good morning friends,
We are but a couple weeks away from Christmas having officially rung the bells of another Christmas season. Albeit, it is far from the traditional in store experiences of long lines snaking through the store and popping out at the seams. This year, across the globe our store fronts have transitioned to the internet. And there are some great advantages of it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Generative WebAssembly Music, Climate Change and Exploring Differential Growth</title>
      <link>https://chrisried.xyz/newsletter/generative-arts-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chrisried.xyz/newsletter/generative-arts-7/</guid>
      <description>Originally posted on Substack
&amp;ldquo;Curiosity is the main energy&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo; - Robert Rauschenberg
Here in the US, we just celebrated Thanksgiving Day, but with this unfortunate year; many of us have not been able to see our family due to restrictions, lock downs, etc. Yet there are always things that we can be thankful. For me is technology, programming languages and the ability to create using them and have done alot more this year than I have done in previously.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multiplayer Stable Diffusion, Song of Life, and Simulating Rope</title>
      <link>https://chrisried.xyz/newsletter/generative-arts-54/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chrisried.xyz/newsletter/generative-arts-54/</guid>
      <description>Originally posted on Substack
The need to be right all the time is the biggest bar there is to new ideas. -Edward D Bono
Good morning!
Hope you have had a great week!
This week I’ve a few links to some musical platforms. Hope you find some inspiration to make some interesting works by simply experimenting with various implementations. There are definitely way more ways to do this out there but I’d highlight some of the less frequently used visual programming platforms for your enjoyment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cloud Fractals, Blooms, and Spinning Parametrics</title>
      <link>https://chrisried.xyz/newsletter/generative-arts-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chrisried.xyz/newsletter/generative-arts-6/</guid>
      <description>Originally posted on Substack
&amp;ldquo;The greatest value of a picture is when it forces us to notice what we never expected to see.&amp;rdquo; -John Tukey
Hello friends,
I hope that you all have had another amazing week being creative.
A bunch of you have left feedback that you want to see more code; and so I have added a section called &amp;ldquo;Snippet of the Week&amp;rdquo; in which I will highlight shorter pieces of code that inspire me to further play with it and mutate it to being something else.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Generative Art, Touch Designer and Genuary 2021</title>
      <link>https://chrisried.xyz/newsletter/generative-arts-14/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chrisried.xyz/newsletter/generative-arts-14/</guid>
      <description>Originally posted on Substack
The art of resting the mind and the power of dismissing from it all care and worry is probably one of the secrets of our great men. - Captain J. A. Hatfield
My apologies for not being able to put together a newsletter last week. There was so much going on in the week that I hadn&amp;rsquo;t found the bandwidth to put it together and then needed a little R&amp;amp;D over the weekend.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Poetic Gameplay, Emergent Structures, and Bending Light</title>
      <link>https://chrisried.xyz/newsletter/generative-arts-30/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chrisried.xyz/newsletter/generative-arts-30/</guid>
      <description>Originally posted on Substack
&amp;ldquo;scattered star-light falls a faint birdsong on the water&amp;rsquo;s surface&amp;rdquo; - Wayfinder
The poem was the generative haiku that was generated as I played through Wayfinder. What is it you ask?
Wayfinder is a web-based generative art game that takes the player on a contemplative cause-and-effect journey through nature. Symbolizing the give-and-take relationship humans have with the natural world, players move a mystical character through forest, grasslands and tundra in search of poetic tokens dotting the landscape.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is the Future of Generative Art?</title>
      <link>https://chrisried.xyz/newsletter/generative-arts-36/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chrisried.xyz/newsletter/generative-arts-36/</guid>
      <description>Originally posted on Substack
&amp;ldquo;A blank canvas&amp;hellip;has unlimited possibilities.&amp;rdquo; - Stephanie Perkins
I&amp;rsquo;ve spent a significant amount of time thinking about the question,
What does generative art looks like in the future? When reading through the hurdles that 60s technology (and earlier) was able to produce and I have to sit and ponder. With their limitations in processing, cost and storage, input constraints, technical abilities, one has to stop and think about what does pushing those bounds look like today.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Generating Surprise, Algoart w/ Flutter and Natural Processes</title>
      <link>https://chrisried.xyz/newsletter/generative-arts-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chrisried.xyz/newsletter/generative-arts-5/</guid>
      <description>Originally posted on Substack
“All art is quite useless.” — but maybe useless is what we need right now. Oscar Wilde
Hello Friends!
This week has been a wonderful week full of interesting links and experimentation for myself and I hope that they were the same for you.
Below there is an article called &amp;ldquo;A CRITIQUE OF SURPRISE IN GENERATIVE ART&amp;rdquo; that has left interesting questions on the validity of generative art in light of artwork from the postmodern periods.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Feynman, Algorithmic Orchestration and Node Based Programming</title>
      <link>https://chrisried.xyz/newsletter/generative-arts-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chrisried.xyz/newsletter/generative-arts-4/</guid>
      <description>Creativity is allowing yourself to make mistakes. Art is knowing which ones to keep.&amp;quot; - Scott Adams
This last week I finished the book, &amp;ldquo;Your Joking Mr. Feynman&amp;rdquo; and I have to say that Feynman would have loved to work in the Generative Arts. (And by the way, this is a great listen (free w/ Audible subscription.) . A greatly influential scientist of the 20th century but not your lab rat; but one who would have done almost anything to experience.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Arc Wheels</title>
      <link>https://chrisried.xyz/projects/arc-wheels/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chrisried.xyz/projects/arc-wheels/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Generative Arts Weekly #003</title>
      <link>https://chrisried.xyz/newsletter/generative-arts-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chrisried.xyz/newsletter/generative-arts-3/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;You can&amp;rsquo;t use up creativity. The more you use, the more you have.&amp;rdquo; - Maya Angelou
This week&amp;rsquo;s letter is a little delayed due to being on vacation and trying to get in as much beach time before the tropical storms come. But it is always empowering to listen to the ocean and the sound that it makes. I mean the very nature of chaos that it controls due to the power of the waves is astounding.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Analytics to Determine Ideal Hashtags for Instagram</title>
      <link>https://chrisried.xyz/posts/using-analytics-to-determine-ideal-hashtags/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chrisried.xyz/posts/using-analytics-to-determine-ideal-hashtags/</guid>
      <description>library(stringr) library(readr) library(tidyverse) library(lubridate) I have been curious on what makes an interesting post on instagram based on a larger dataset of images that have been tagged with #generativeart. Some of this is just data discovery, this could seem that there may be a correlation between the tags that have been used and the amount of likes there are.
# Extract hashtags patt &amp;lt;- regex(&amp;#34;#\\S+&amp;#34;) genart &amp;lt;- read_csv(&amp;#34;~/InstaCrawlR/table-generativeart-2020-10-11 13:35:33.csv&amp;#34;) genart_db &amp;lt;- genart %&amp;gt;% select(ID, Likes, Owner, Date, Text) %&amp;gt;% mutate(hashtags = str_extract_all(Text,patt) ) genart_db_table &amp;lt;- genart_db %&amp;gt;% unnest(cols = &amp;#34;hashtags&amp;#34;) %&amp;gt;% mutate(Year = year(Date), Month = month(Date), DayOfWeek = wday(Date), Day = day(Date), Hour = hour(Date)) genart_db_table %&amp;gt;% head() That will generate a rather large dataset</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Generative Arts Weekly #002</title>
      <link>https://chrisried.xyz/newsletter/generative-arts-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chrisried.xyz/newsletter/generative-arts-2/</guid>
      <description>“ Devour old films, new films, music, books, paintings, photographs, poems, dreams, random conversations, architecture, bridges, street signs, trees, clouds, bodies of water, light, and shadows. Select only things to steal from that speak directly to your soul. If you do this, your work (and theft) will be authentic. Authenticity is invaluable; originality is non-existent. And don&amp;rsquo;t bother concealing your thievery - celebrate it if you feel like it. In any case, always remember what Jean-Luc Godard said: Worry not where you take things from - it&amp;rsquo;s where you take them to.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to NLP using Python</title>
      <link>https://chrisried.xyz/posts/introduction-to-nlp-using-python/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chrisried.xyz/posts/introduction-to-nlp-using-python/</guid>
      <description>The following post is using SpaCy to do all of the NLP work. Throughout the following post we will cover a number of different NLP tasks that are foundational to the work that can be built upon to generate complex syntatical modelling.
Tokenization This process takes any body of text (more specifically a Document) and breaks it down either to the sentence level or the word level.
import spacy nlp = spacy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bayesian Statistics in R</title>
      <link>https://chrisried.xyz/posts/bayesian-statistics-in-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chrisried.xyz/posts/bayesian-statistics-in-r/</guid>
      <description>Bayesian Statistics The following documents the standard Bayesian Statistics occurs.
Some of the key differences you will find behind the more traditional frequentist statistics and Bayesian methodologies are as follows:
Prior statistical distributions are updated as new information becomes available. </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Generative Arts Weekly #001</title>
      <link>https://chrisried.xyz/newsletter/generative-arts-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chrisried.xyz/newsletter/generative-arts-1/</guid>
      <description>Originally posted on Substack
“Nothing&amp;rsquo;s perfect, the world&amp;rsquo;s not perfect. But it&amp;rsquo;s there for us, trying the best it can; that&amp;rsquo;s what makes it so beautiful.” - Hiromu Arakaw
The beauty of art is that it is experimental, its emotional, it&amp;rsquo;s spiritual and as an artist, it helps better understand who we are and why we are by expressing the inner self. It can be a medium of unity, it can be a cry for anarchy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fleur-d-Square</title>
      <link>https://chrisried.xyz/projects/fleur-d-square/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chrisried.xyz/projects/fleur-d-square/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Catch Fraud with Deep Learning</title>
      <link>https://chrisried.xyz/posts/how-to-catch-fraud-with-deep-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chrisried.xyz/posts/how-to-catch-fraud-with-deep-learning/</guid>
      <description>Fraud continues to be an important topic in the financial world helping detect when funds are mismanaged.
Nilson reports that U.S. card fraud (credit, debt, etc) was reportedly $9 billion in 2016 and expected to increase to $12 billion by 2020. Due to these nefarious acts; it is in the best interest of any organization to ensure the work of most customers. Thus it is appropriate to respond to this fraud.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brush Fade</title>
      <link>https://chrisried.xyz/projects/brush-fade/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chrisried.xyz/projects/brush-fade/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shape Shifting</title>
      <link>https://chrisried.xyz/projects/shape-shifting/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chrisried.xyz/projects/shape-shifting/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Formatting Currencies in R</title>
      <link>https://chrisried.xyz/posts/2018-08-21-formatting-currencies-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chrisried.xyz/posts/2018-08-21-formatting-currencies-r/</guid>
      <description>Here are a few ways to format numbers in R for presentations. A few of theme can be accomplished using the paste function in R. I&amp;rsquo;ve found that there are a few different methods to do this.
Using the scales package Using the scales packages from Hadley, there is a great function with various options including passing a vector.
library(scales) dollar_format()(c(-100, 0.23, 1.456565, 2e3)) Formatting currency with separator Following is a simple function one can build and place in their utility function that will give formatted currency.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to bend the data</title>
      <link>https://chrisried.xyz/posts/how-to-bend-the-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chrisried.xyz/posts/how-to-bend-the-data/</guid>
      <description>One of the fundamental priorities of a data scientist is being able to bend the data into a format that is plyable. Being able to effectively use tidyr, reshape2 and the core functions are key to success in being able to manage a large dataset without swimming or drowning in it.
But it does take discipline and instinct to understand the validity of the data so lets exercise this a little:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Phillips Hue in R</title>
      <link>https://chrisried.xyz/posts/phillips-hue-in-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chrisried.xyz/posts/phillips-hue-in-r/</guid>
      <description>The following function can be used to find and display the internal IP address needed to retrieve the IP address from Hue Bridge. You will need to generate an API key i.e. a &amp;ldquo;userkey&amp;rdquo; as I called it below.
getIP &amp;lt;- function() { url &amp;lt;- paste0(&amp;#34;https://www.meethue.com/api/nupnp&amp;#34;) res &amp;lt;- httpGET(url) resJson &amp;lt;- fromJSON(res) res &amp;lt;- resJson[[&amp;#34;internalipaddress&amp;#34;]] res } In order to know what light you should change the state on, one can run the following to retrieve the available lights connected on the network.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simulate Doctor Visit Resource Planning Using Simmer</title>
      <link>https://chrisried.xyz/posts/simulate-resource-planning-using-simmer/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chrisried.xyz/posts/simulate-resource-planning-using-simmer/</guid>
      <description>Here I&amp;rsquo;ve tried to come up with a simple layout on how we might simulate doctor&amp;rsquo;s visits.
Following code tries to resource plan certain doctor visits based on the vignette that was provided with the simmer package.
library(simmer) set.seed(42) env &amp;lt;- simmer(&amp;#34;SuperDuperSim&amp;#34;) env patient &amp;lt;- trajectory(&amp;#34;patients&amp;#39; path&amp;#34;) %&amp;gt;% ## add an intake activity seize(&amp;#34;nurse&amp;#34;, 1) %&amp;gt;% timeout(function() rnorm(1, 15)) %&amp;gt;% release(&amp;#34;nurse&amp;#34;, 1) %&amp;gt;% ## add a consultation activity seize(&amp;#34;doctor&amp;#34;, 1) %&amp;gt;% timeout(function() rnorm(1, 20)) %&amp;gt;% release(&amp;#34;doctor&amp;#34;, 1) %&amp;gt;% ## add a planning activity seize(&amp;#34;administration&amp;#34;, 1) %&amp;gt;% timeout(function() rnorm(1, 5)) %&amp;gt;% release(&amp;#34;administration&amp;#34;, 1) env %&amp;gt;% add_resource(&amp;#34;nurse&amp;#34;, 1) %&amp;gt;% add_resource(&amp;#34;doctor&amp;#34;, 2) %&amp;gt;% add_resource(&amp;#34;administration&amp;#34;, 1) %&amp;gt;% add_generator(&amp;#34;patient&amp;#34;, patient, function() rnorm(1, 10, 2)) env %&amp;gt;% run(80) %&amp;gt;% now() env %&amp;gt;% peek(3) env %&amp;gt;% stepn() %&amp;gt;% # 1 step print() %&amp;gt;% stepn(3) # 3 steps envs &amp;lt;- lapply(1:100, function(i) { simmer(&amp;#34;SuperDuperSim&amp;#34;) %&amp;gt;% add_resource(&amp;#34;nurse&amp;#34;, 1) %&amp;gt;% add_resource(&amp;#34;doctor&amp;#34;, 2) %&amp;gt;% add_resource(&amp;#34;administration&amp;#34;, 1) %&amp;gt;% add_generator(&amp;#34;patient&amp;#34;, patient, function() rnorm(1, 10, 2)) %&amp;gt;% run(80) }) envs %&amp;gt;% get_mon_resources() %&amp;gt;% head() envs %&amp;gt;% get_mon_arrivals() %&amp;gt;% head() </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Take Back Your Time (Evernote)</title>
      <link>https://chrisried.xyz/posts/take-back-your-time-evernote/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chrisried.xyz/posts/take-back-your-time-evernote/</guid>
      <description>You will find the following text originally posted on Medium</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Time and Difficulty</title>
      <link>https://chrisried.xyz/posts/time-and-difficulty/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chrisried.xyz/posts/time-and-difficulty/</guid>
      <description>Sometimes, seeing data in a 3 dimensional space gives us better visibility to the rest of the world. You will see that we have taken a hypothetical experiment and tried to rate different ideas by their complexity and likelihood to succeed.
#Libraries to import library(tidyverse) library(plotly) # Intellectual matrix idea &amp;lt;- c(&amp;#34;Build a spaceship&amp;#34;,&amp;#34;Create a new social platform&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;Build a birdhouse&amp;#34;,&amp;#34;Collect 10000 friends&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;Clip toenails&amp;#34;,&amp;#34;Build a spaceship&amp;#34;,&amp;#34;Create a new social platform&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;Build a birdhouse&amp;#34;,&amp;#34;Collect 10000 friends&amp;#34;,&amp;#34;Build a spaceship&amp;#34;,&amp;#34;Create a new social platform&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;Build a birdhouse&amp;#34;,&amp;#34;Collect 10000 friends&amp;#34;,&amp;#34;Build a spaceship&amp;#34;,&amp;#34;Create a new social platform&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;Build a birdhouse&amp;#34;,&amp;#34;Collect 10000 friends&amp;#34;) time &amp;lt;- c(5,5,2,3,1,5,5,2,3,5,5,2,3,1,5,5,2) difficulty &amp;lt;- c(5,4,2,3,1,5,4,2,3,5,5,2,3,1,5,5,2) favorability &amp;lt;- c(2,5,2,1,3,4,1,2,1,2,5,2,1,3,3,1,2) #Creates the dataframe dataset &amp;lt;- data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Minature Generative Art</title>
      <link>https://chrisried.xyz/posts/minature-generative-art/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chrisried.xyz/posts/minature-generative-art/</guid>
      <description>Sometimes something simple can turn out to generate the most beautiful things. Following you will find a few lines of code that present a beautiful pattern.
library(ggplot2) library(dplyr) Oval Curve n &amp;lt;- 300 t1 &amp;lt;- 1:n t0 &amp;lt;- seq(3,2*n+1,2) %% n t2 &amp;lt;- t0 + (t0 == 0)*n df &amp;lt;- data.frame(x = cos((t1-1)*2*pi/n), y = sin((t1-1)*2*pi/n), x2 = cos((t2-1)*2*pi/n), y2 = sin((t2-1)*2*pi/n)) ggplot(df,aes(x,y,xend = x2,yend = y2)) + geom_segment(alpha = .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Extracting Hyperlinks from an XSLX in R</title>
      <link>https://chrisried.xyz/posts/extracting-hyperlinks-from-an-xslx-in-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chrisried.xyz/posts/extracting-hyperlinks-from-an-xslx-in-r/</guid>
      <description>In Progress install.packages(&amp;#34;keras&amp;#34;) library(keras) devtools::install_github(&amp;#34;omarwagih/ggseqlogo&amp;#34;) devtools::install_github(&amp;#34;leonjessen/PepTools&amp;#34;) </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Human Ingenuity and Speed</title>
      <link>https://chrisried.xyz/posts/human-ingenuity-and-speed/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chrisried.xyz/posts/human-ingenuity-and-speed/</guid>
      <description>library(tidyverse) Data Building
The first thing we need to understand is where we have come and where we are going. There is alot that has been done in the past couple years but we still have more.
type &amp;lt;- c(&amp;#34;Sound&amp;#34;,&amp;#34;Light&amp;#34;,&amp;#34;Human Travel&amp;#34;) units &amp;lt;- c(&amp;#34;mps&amp;#34;,&amp;#34;mps&amp;#34;,&amp;#34;mps&amp;#34;) speed &amp;lt;- c(343,299792458,11082.569) source &amp;lt;- c(&amp;#34;&amp;#34;,&amp;#34;&amp;#34;,&amp;#34;&amp;#34;) speed_data &amp;lt;- data.frame(type,units, speed,source) spd &amp;lt;- speed_data$speed spd %*% (t(spd)) &amp;ndash;TODO: The following
299792458/11082.57 Human History of Speed Speed hasn&amp;rsquo;t been a</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Words With Friends Musings</title>
      <link>https://chrisried.xyz/posts/words-with-friends-musings/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chrisried.xyz/posts/words-with-friends-musings/</guid>
      <description>Words with Friends is a wonderful game full of
#library(tidyverse) # IMport Data #filepath &amp;lt;- &amp;#34;~/Dropbox/Word Lists/WordsWithFriends/enable1-wwf-v4.0-wordlist.txt&amp;#34; #wwfList &amp;lt;- read_csv(filepath, col_names = FALSE) #wwfList %&amp;gt;% stringr::str(&amp;#39;.ae.&amp;#39;) </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring the Book of Esther in the Tidy Verse</title>
      <link>https://chrisried.xyz/posts/exploring-the-book-of-esther-in-the-tidy-verse/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chrisried.xyz/posts/exploring-the-book-of-esther-in-the-tidy-verse/</guid>
      <description>library(httr) library(tidytext) library(jsonlite) library(tidyverse) library(wordcloud) library(XML) source(&amp;#34;~/keys.R&amp;#34;) key &amp;lt;- biblia There is much to be learned in the form of writing and the relationship it has within and outside the text. The question we might want to ask is there a way to identify the story arc of the situation. Using spacy to tag all of the words will increase the likelyhood to better understand the
style &amp;lt;- &amp;#34;oneVersePerLineFullReference&amp;#34; #oneVersePerLine, bibleTextOnly, oneVersePerLineFullReference output &amp;lt;- &amp;#34;html&amp;#34; passage &amp;lt;-&amp;#34;Esther1-10&amp;#34; resp &amp;lt;- GET(paste0(&amp;#34;https://api.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Timeseries Analysis Using R and Advantager</title>
      <link>https://chrisried.xyz/posts/timeseries-analysis-using-r-and-advantager/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chrisried.xyz/posts/timeseries-analysis-using-r-and-advantager/</guid>
      <description>Threw error due to the API In the past, the best way to get stock prices was to use either Google Finance or Yahoo Finance data streams. These have since become difficult to keep up to date and thus another outlet to get this information is AlphaVantager. Following is a simple R implementation to get up to date data. You will be able to thus use this to find the information.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Text Generation</title>
      <link>https://chrisried.xyz/posts/text-generation/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chrisried.xyz/posts/text-generation/</guid>
      <description>IN PROGRESS Text Generation (Generative Texr) is a very interesting field of study. There are a number of different packages that help generate the lists of words to give the user a better understanding of the technology.
Tracery The following Node library gives a structure which is used to generate random words that are assigned to lexical structure that is defined by the user.
centar : { animal : [&amp;#34;wolf&amp;#34;,&amp;#34;bear&amp;#34;,&amp;#34;tiger&amp;#34;,&amp;#34;lion&amp;#34;,&amp;#34;snake&amp;#34;,&amp;#34;anteater&amp;#34;], fruit : [&amp;#34;banana&amp;#34;,&amp;#34;tomato&amp;#34;,&amp;#34;cherry&amp;#34;,&amp;#34;strawberry&amp;#34;,&amp;#34;starfruit&amp;#34;], said : [&amp;#34;purring&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;whispering&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;saying&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;murmurring&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;growling&amp;#34;], timeofday : [&amp;#34;morning&amp;#34;,&amp;#34;evening&amp;#34;,&amp;#34;dusk&amp;#34;,&amp;#34;dawn&amp;#34;,&amp;#34;afternoon&amp;#34;,&amp;#34;breakfast&amp;#34;,&amp;#34;breakfast&amp;#34;], lastSyl : &amp;#34;a ia ea u y en am is on an o io i el ios ax ox ix ex izz ius ian ean ekang anth&amp;#34;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gantt Charts in R</title>
      <link>https://chrisried.xyz/posts/gantt-charts-in-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chrisried.xyz/posts/gantt-charts-in-r/</guid>
      <description>In Progress Using timevis library(timevis) data &amp;lt;- data.frame( id = 1:4, content = c(&amp;#34;Item one&amp;#34; , &amp;#34;Item two&amp;#34; ,&amp;#34;Ranged item&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;Item four&amp;#34;), start = c(&amp;#34;2016-01-10&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;2016-01-11&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;2016-01-20&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;2016-02-14 15:00:00&amp;#34;), end = c(NA , NA, &amp;#34;2016-02-04&amp;#34;, NA) ) timevis(data) Using DiagrammerR library(tidyr) library(dplyr) library(DiagrammeR) mermaid(&amp;#34; gantt dateFormat YYYY-MM-DD title A Very Nice Gantt Diagram section Basic Tasks This is completed :done, first_1, 2014-01-06, 2014-01-08 This is active :active, first_2, 2014-01-09, 3d Do this later : first_3, after first_2, 5d Do this after that : first_4, after first_3, 5d section Important Things Completed, critical task :crit, done, import_1, 2014-01-06,24h Also done, also critical :crit, done, import_2, after import_1, 2d Doing this important task now :crit, active, import_3, after import_2, 3d Next critical task :crit, import_4, after import_3, 5d section The Extras First extras :active, extras_1, after import_4, 3d Second helping : extras_2, after extras_1, 20h More of the extras : extras_3, after extras_1, 48h &amp;#34;) Using Plotly If you wanted to use a more</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tips on Feature Engineering</title>
      <link>https://chrisried.xyz/posts/2017-10-08-feature-engineering/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chrisried.xyz/posts/2017-10-08-feature-engineering/</guid>
      <description>Tips on Feature Engineering to fit how classifiers work; giving a geometry problem to a tree, oversized dimension to a kNN and interval data to an SVM are not a good ideas remove as much nonlinearities as possible; expecting that some classifier will do Fourier analysis inside is rather naive (even if, it will waste a lot of complexity there) make features generic to all objects so that some sampling in the chain won&amp;rsquo;t knock them out check previous works &amp;ndash; often transformation used for visualisation or testing similar types of data is already tuned to uncover interesting aspects avoid unstable, optimizing transformations like PCA which may lead to overfitting experiment a lot </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Great Statistics Books to Read</title>
      <link>https://chrisried.xyz/posts/great-statistics-books-to-read/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chrisried.xyz/posts/great-statistics-books-to-read/</guid>
      <description>Following you will find a number of the best books to learn more about statistics and its philosophy.
Opinionated Lessons on Statistics Introduction to Statistical Learning The Elements of Statistical Learning Applied Predicitive Modeling Statistical Inference Statistical Rethinking Data Analysis Using Regression and Multilevel/Hierarchical Models Mostly Harmless Econometrics Mastering Metrics: The Path from Cause to Effect All of Statistics Statistics Statistics for Experimenters Think Bayes Computer Age Statistical Inference Think Stats Machine Learning for Hackers Probability and Statistics Statistical Evidence: A likelihood paradigm </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AB Testing in R from Scratch</title>
      <link>https://chrisried.xyz/posts/ab-testing-in-r-from-scratch/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chrisried.xyz/posts/ab-testing-in-r-from-scratch/</guid>
      <description>Using Bayesian Systems Quantify the probability of all possibilites thus measuring risk insert institutional knowledge (add knowledge that changes the probability) learn in an online fashion A/B Testing with Approximate Bayesian Computation No mathematics required able to implement from scratch A/B Testing Measures and figures out the better design
Approximate Bayesian Computation
Generate a trial value for the thing we want to know (in this case its the conversion fraction of a layout) Simulate or data assuming the trail value, keep the trial value, otherwise discard it and try again If the simulation looks like the real data, keep the trial value, otherwise discard and try again Keep doing this until we&amp;rsquo;ve got lots of trial values that worked library(progress) library(ggplot2) library(reshape2) # Variables n_visitors_a &amp;lt;- 100 # number of visitors shown layout A n_conv_a &amp;lt;- 4 # number of vistors shown layout A who converted (4%) n_visitors_b &amp;lt;- 40 n_conv_b &amp;lt;- 2 Using Bayesian Systems</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tips on Creating Effective and Functional Documentation in R</title>
      <link>https://chrisried.xyz/posts/tips-creating-functional-documention/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chrisried.xyz/posts/tips-creating-functional-documention/</guid>
      <description>Just like any skill, there is a learning curve involved in creating effective communication. This involves the code written and the documentation of its usage. Writing functional code is a intricate thing to accomplish as a newbie. It takes time to know what is efficient and how to communicate it as such. Now, writing functional documentation is more complicated as there is a delicate balance between not reguritate what the code says, and giving usable pointers to the users on how a particular function was intended to be used.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tracking Change Improvements in Retail</title>
      <link>https://chrisried.xyz/posts/tracking-change-improvements-in-retail/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chrisried.xyz/posts/tracking-change-improvements-in-retail/</guid>
      <description>In the ever changing world of retail; one always has to keep one step ahead of the competition and to engage with its customers. One of the best ways
Formulate a test Implement Test Evaluate results Adjust the test Try again. These are all great ideas, but how do we truly watch tas things get better?
library(qcc) library(xtable) library(SixSigma) library(qicharts) Cause and Effect Diagrams cManpower &amp;lt;- c(&amp;#34;Recepcionist&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;Record. Operator&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;Storage operators&amp;#34;) cMaterials &amp;lt;- c(&amp;#34;Supplier&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;Transport agency&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;Packing&amp;#34;) cMachines &amp;lt;- c(&amp;#34;Compressor type&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;Operation conditions&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;Machine adjustment&amp;#34;) cMethods &amp;lt;- c(&amp;#34;Reception&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;Transport method&amp;#34;) cMeasurements &amp;lt;- c(&amp;#34;Recording method&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;Measurement appraisal&amp;#34;) cGroups &amp;lt;- c(&amp;#34;Manpower&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;Materials&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;Machines&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;Methods&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;Measurements&amp;#34;) cEffect &amp;lt;- &amp;#34;Too high density&amp;#34; cause.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rocket Propulsion</title>
      <link>https://chrisried.xyz/posts/rocket-propolsion/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chrisried.xyz/posts/rocket-propolsion/</guid>
      <description>library(tidyverse) Accelerating force
$$ F=mv_e $$ thrust of the rocket is expressed in terms of the *mass flow rate * m and the efficient exhaust velocity \(v_e\)
$$ V = V_e\log_e\frac{M_0}{M} $$ $M_0$ - mass of the rocket at ignition $M$ - Current mass of the rocket
mass ratio $$ R = \frac{M_0}{M} $$
AcceleratedForce &amp;lt;- function(m,v.e) { m*v.e } RocketEquation &amp;lt;- function(mass.ratio, exhaust.velocity) { exhaust.velocity*log(mass.ratio, base = exp(1)) } RocketEquationGraph &amp;lt;- data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creative Sinkholes</title>
      <link>https://chrisried.xyz/writings/creative-sinkholes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chrisried.xyz/writings/creative-sinkholes/</guid>
      <description>Believing that something is crap, is creative indigestion. It inhibits your power to create, sucks your soul&amp;rsquo;s happiness and breeds stress and rejection. It becomes a waste of time, rather than further develop. We discontinue this crap that we have mistaken as no creativity. This is a perception that needs to be overcome and dealt with. But how do you overcome?
Don&amp;rsquo;t Limit your Creativity As people we generally want to be like the Jones.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cloud Fractals, Blooms, and Spinning Parametrics</title>
      <link>https://chrisried.xyz/newsletter/generative-arts-52/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chrisried.xyz/newsletter/generative-arts-52/</guid>
      <description>The Creator’s Formula is made up of four key elements: defined purpose, experienced creativity, flawless execution, and emotional -Alan Phillips
Hello fellow readers,
Hope your Friday morning / afternoon is going well. There are a number of interesting links below for you to digest and swallow.
And for just a little inspiration…
If you haven’t seen the work by Tyler Boswell definitely check out his work September
https://twitter.com/cosipiovasc0/status/1577370812624998400?s=20&amp;amp;t=JvG3Se3lkkg-r9GIcmg2Ew
Have a wonderful weekend!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
