<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>generative art on Artistic Portfolio of Chris Ried</title>
    <link>https://chrisried.xyz/tags/generative-art/</link>
    <description>Recent content in generative art on Artistic Portfolio of Chris Ried</description>
    <image>
      <url>https://chrisried.xyz/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://chrisried.xyz/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://chrisried.xyz/tags/generative-art/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How to Create Generative Art</title>
      <link>https://chrisried.xyz/posts/2022-10-26-how-to-make-generative-art/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chrisried.xyz/posts/2022-10-26-how-to-make-generative-art/</guid>
      <description>Following are 10 ways how to start learning how to make generative art.
Learn how to use a framework or software for generative art. There are a number of different ways to do this. Here is a mindmap as a guide. I&amp;rsquo;d suggest just looking at them and start searching for them.
Take a few art classes There are plenty of places online such as Domestika or Skillshare that will help you find inspiration, and open your mind to new ideas of expression.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lined Up Imperfectly</title>
      <link>https://chrisried.xyz/projects/lined-up-imperfectly/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chrisried.xyz/projects/lined-up-imperfectly/</guid>
      <description>The collection has clothlike qualities but still lies in fundamental structures as we experiment and try to understand the intersection between the rigid and fluid.
#1
#2
#3
#4</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Celestial Collisions</title>
      <link>https://chrisried.xyz/projects/celestial-collisions/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chrisried.xyz/projects/celestial-collisions/</guid>
      <description>The following project spanned across 800 editions that were released on FXHash in Dec 2021. Conceptually, this was a meditation on scale and collision. Scale is intuitively misunderstood by humans. We have a poor judgement how big, or how small things really are as we do not have a reference of comparison.
It may be due to the fact that these scales are recent discoveries.
We have seen stars for millenium, but we have not had a good understanding at their size until&amp;hellip; The same goes for really small items.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Geometric Meditations</title>
      <link>https://chrisried.xyz/projects/geometric-meditations/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chrisried.xyz/projects/geometric-meditations/</guid>
      <description>These are some of my favorite things.. the grid and then building an image inside each of the grids has a sense of satisfaction to me. I am not quite sure what that is, but it is quite swell.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Like The Emperors Robe</title>
      <link>https://chrisried.xyz/projects/emperors-robe/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chrisried.xyz/projects/emperors-robe/</guid>
      <description>The following generative piece appears like the robe of an emperor. When looking closely, you will find that each square is unique as it builds a web of fabric. You can find the pieces on Objkt</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
