<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>golang on Technical Portfolio of Chris Ried</title>
    <link>https://chrisried.xyz/categories/golang/</link>
    <description>Recent content in golang on Technical Portfolio of Chris Ried</description>
    <image>
      <url>https://chrisried.xyz/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://chrisried.xyz/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://chrisried.xyz/categories/golang/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Blockchain Analytics</title>
      <link>https://chrisried.xyz/posts/blockchain-landscape/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chrisried.xyz/posts/blockchain-landscape/</guid>
      <description>The following post provides some context around the many many different technologies that are currently out there in the blockchain space. Much of these are changing on a monthly basis with new things coming out all the time. So I thought it might be good to have a document that tries to compile what this landscape currently looks like in 2022.
See the Pen Untitled by Chris Ried (@cdr6934) on CodePen.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating a New Theme</title>
      <link>https://chrisried.xyz/posts/creating-a-new-theme/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chrisried.xyz/posts/creating-a-new-theme/</guid>
      <description>Introduction This tutorial will show you how to create a simple theme in Hugo. I assume that you are familiar with HTML, the bash command line, and that you are comfortable using Markdown to format content. I&amp;rsquo;ll explain how Hugo uses templates and how you can organize your templates to create a theme. I won&amp;rsquo;t cover using CSS to style your theme.
We&amp;rsquo;ll start with creating a new site with a very basic template.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Create Generative Art</title>
      <link>https://chrisried.xyz/posts/how-to-make-generative-art/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chrisried.xyz/posts/how-to-make-generative-art/</guid>
      <description>Following are 10 ways how to start learning how to make generative art.
Learn how to use a framework or software for generative art. There are a number of different ways to do this. Here is a mindmap as a guide. I&amp;rsquo;d suggest just looking at them and start searching for them.
Take a few art classes There are plenty of places online such as Domestika or Skillshare that will help you find inspiration, and open your mind to new ideas of expression.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
